

396 Engineering VI, University of California, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1596

□ (+1)310 307 9986 | Zhiyi.zhang@ucla.edu | 🛪 www.zhiyi-zhang.com | 🖸 zhiyi-zhang | 🛅 zhiyi-zhang

Summary _

Fifth-year PhD candidate in computer science at UCLA. My research interests fall into /system/security, with an emphasis on problems that broadly impact society. My research projects includes security and privacy enhancement in network systems, distributed systems, and data engineering. Since I started my Ph.D., I am trying to identify and solve real-world security and privacy issues.

Education

UCLA Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Supervised by Professor Lixia Zhang in the Internet Research Laboratory.
- Research fields: Network Security, Internet of Things, Information-centric Network
- Teaching Assistant of Graduate Course: Internet Architecture and Protocols
- Teaching Assistant of Undergraduate Courses: Software Construction, Computer Network

Nankai Univ. Tianjin, China

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

- Graduated with distinction: Outstanding Graduate Student Award in 2016
- The National Scholarship of China in 2015
- Earned GPA of 3.8/4.0

Experience

Internet Research Laboratory, UCLA

Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

Sep. 2016 - Exp. Jun. 2021

DOCTORAL RESEARCHER

Sep. 2016 - PRESENT

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2016

- Project lead of NDN-Lite, a NDN-based IoT Framework which enables user's local control of smart home systems.
- Project lead of El PASSO, a privacy-preserving and asynchronous **Single Sign-on** with randomizable signature and zero-knowledge proof.
- A Personally Identifiable Information(PII) sharing system with **reliable leaking source identification**.
- · Project lead for the design and development of a graph-based permissioned distributed ledger system.
- Designed and implemented a NDN-based **DDoS defense** system to mitigate DDoS attacks.
- Research and Development for **Access Control Scheme** and **Certificate Management** over NDN.

Transport Security team, Facebook

(Remote) Menlo Park, CA, U.S.

Jun. 2020 - Sep. 2020

- DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Implemented the first-ever } \textbf{TLS Batch Signature} \ \text{in Fizz library for TLS 1.3 to boost TLS performance}.$
- Finishing a set of benchmark tools in Facebook Fizz library for **TLS 1.3 benchmarking**.
- Adding new features including Merkle Tree and NSS Key Log into Facebook Fizz library.

Infrastructure Service (AIS) team, Alibaba

Bellevue, WA, U.S.

Jun. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- RESEARCH&DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP
- Building high-performance user-mode network stack by adjusting QUIC to work with kernel bypass (DPDK)
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Evaluation of QUIC+DPDK's performance compared with TCP+TLS+HTTP/2} \ and \ DPDK+TCP+TLS+HTTP/2$
- Explored new congestion control protocol (BBR) in data center network scenario

Research Publications

Get access to all the publications: https://zhiyi-zhang.com/publications.html

PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE AND JOURNAL PAPERS

EL PASSO: PIRVACY-PRESERVING ASYNCHRONOUS SINGLE SIGN-ON PETS 2021

2021

Zhiyi Zhang, Michał Król, Alberto Sonnino, Lixia Zhang, Etienne Rivière

RAPIDVFETCH: RAPID DOWNLOADING OF NAMED DATA VIA DISTRIBUTED V2V COMMUNICATION

2019

IEEE Vehicular Networking Conference (VNC), pp. 290-297, Dec 2019

Zhiyi Zhang, Tianxiang Li, John Dellaverson, Lixia Zhang

JANUARY 8, 2021 ZHIYI ZHANG · CURRICULUM VITAE

IEEE Communications Magazine, Volume:57, Issue:7, July 2019 Yanbiao Li, Zhiyi Zhang , Xin Wang, Edward Lu, Dafang Zhang, Lixia Zhang	2019
PROOF OF AUTHENTICATION FOR PRIVATE DISTRIBUTED LEDGER NDSS on Decentralized IoT Systems and Security (DISS), 2019 Zhiyi Zhang, Vishrant Vasavada, Randy King, Lixia Zhang	2019
Supporting Virtual Organizations Using Attribute-Based Encryption in Named Data Networking IEEE 4th International Conference on Collaboration and Internet Computing (CIC), pp. 188-196, 2018 Craig Lee, Zhiyi Zhang , Yukai Tu, Alex Afanasyev, Lixia Zhang	2018
NAC: AUTOMATING ACCESS CONTROL VIA NAMED DATA IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM), pp. 626-633. IEEE, 2018. Zhiyi Zhang, Yingdi Yu, Sanjeev Kaushik Ramani, Alex Afanasyev, and Lixia Zhang	2018
An Overview of Security Support in Named Data Networking IEEE Communications Magazine, vol. 56, no. 11, pp. 62-68, November 2018. Zhiyi Zhang, H Zhang, E Newberry, S Mastorakis, Y Li, A Afanasyev, L Zhang	2018
NDN Host Model ACM SIGCOMM Computer Communication Review, 48(3), pp.35-41, 2018. H Zhang, Y Li, Zhiyi Zhang , A Afanasyev, Lixia Zhang	2018
NDN DELOREAN: AN AUTHENTICATION SYSTEM FOR DATA ARCHIVES IN NAMED DATA NETWORKING in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking, pp.11-21. ACM, 2017. Yu, Yingdi, Alexander Afanasyev, Jan Seedorf, Zhiyi Zhang , and Lixia Zhang	2017
PEER-REVIEWED SHORT PAPERS & POSTERS	
EVOLVING INTELLIGENT DEVICES FOR THE FUTURE VIA NAMED DATA NETWORKING XRDS: Crossroads, The ACM Magazine for Students, 2019 Zhiyi Zhang , E Lu, Y Guan, T Li, X Ma, Z Kong, L Zhang	2019
NDNoT: A Framework for Named Data Network of Things Best Poster Award in Proceedings of the 5th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2018 Zhiyi Zhang, Edward Lu, Yanbiao Li, Lixia Zhang, Tianyuan Yu, Davide Pesavento, Junxiao Shi, Lotfi Benmohamed	2018
NDNCERT: UNIVERSAL USABLE TRUST MANAGEMENT FOR NDN in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang , Alexander Afanasyev, and Lixia Zhang	2017
in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017.	2017 2017
in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang , Alexander Afanasyev, and Lixia Zhang NAC: NAME-BASED ACCESS CONTROL IN NAMED DATA NETWORKING in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017.	
in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang , Alexander Afanasyev, and Lixia Zhang NAC: NAME-BASED ACCESS CONTROL IN NAMED DATA NETWORKING in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang , Yingdi Yu, Alexander Afanasyev, Jeff Burke, and Lixia Zhang	
in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang, Alexander Afanasyev, and Lixia Zhang NAC: NAME-BASED ACCESS CONTROL IN NAMED DATA NETWORKING in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang, Yingdi Yu, Alexander Afanasyev, Jeff Burke, and Lixia Zhang PREPRINT PAPERS (ONGOING/UNDER-REVIEW) ACTSHARE: SENSITIVE DATA SHARING WITH RELIABLE LEAKER IDENTIFICATION Arxiv Preprint https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.11833	2017
in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang, Alexander Afanasyev, and Lixia Zhang NAC: NAME-BASED ACCESS CONTROL IN NAMED DATA NETWORKING in Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Information-Centric Networking. ACM, 2017. Zhiyi Zhang, Yingdi Yu, Alexander Afanasyev, Jeff Burke, and Lixia Zhang PREPRINT PAPERS (ONGOING/UNDER-REVIEW) ACTSHARE: SENSITIVE DATA SHARING WITH RELIABLE LEAKER IDENTIFICATION Arxiv Preprint https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.11833 Zhiyi Zhang, Yu Guan, Xinyu Ma, Lixia Zhang EXPECT MORE FROM THE NETWORKING: DDOS MITIGATION BY FITT IN NAMED DATA NETWORKING Arxiv Preprint https://arxiv.org/abs/1902.09033	2017 Now

Research Presentation & Talks

Get access to all the talks: https://zhiyi-zhang.com/talks.html

Presenter for NDN-LITE Half-day Tutorial

ACM CONFERENCE ON INFORMATION-CENTRIC NETWORKING (ICN) 2019

Presenter for NDN Security Concepts & Tools Half-day Tutorial

ACM CONFERENCE ON INFORMATION-CENTRIC NETWORKING (ICN) 2018

Macao, China

Sept. 2019

Boston, MA, U.S.

Sept. 2018

Presenter for NDNoT: A Framework for Named Data of Things

NDN COMMUNITY MEETING AT NIST

Presenter for Distributed Ledger over NDN for A Real-world Solar System

NDN COMMUNITY MEETING AT NIST

Gaithersburg, MD, U.S. Sept. 2018

Gaithersburg, MD, U.S.

Sept. 2018

Honors & Awards

2020	Spark Univ. Hackathon Filecoin 2nd Award out of 260 teams , Amount 1k£, Filecoin Pricing Mechanism	Worldwide
2019	UCLA Graduate Division Award, Amount 15k\$, NONRES TUITION GRANT for 2019-2020 academic year.	Los Aneles, U.S.
2018	ACM ICN 2018 Best Poster Award, NDNoT: A Framework for Named Data Network of Things	Boston, U.S.
2016	Outstanding Graduate Student Award, 4 out of 99 in Software Engineering Department, Nankai University	Tianjin, Chind
2015	The National Scholarship of China, 0.2% undergraduates nationwide, Chinese Department of Education	Tianjin, Chind
2015	UCLA CSST Scholarship, Amount 7k\$, Cross-Disciplinary Scholars in Science and Technology, UCLA	Los Angeles, U.S.
2015	Honorable Mention Award, Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM)	Tianjin, Chind